yeah I I have the comments come on the
screen just so that we can get you know
get to talk in and and stuff so we kill
two birds with one we killed two bird
with h sorry with one stone um I'm going
to break here for a second and I'm just
going to acknowledge some of the people
that are in the room okay um so uh Anna
thank you for you like if you could get
if there was a participation award you
would get that award so thank you so
much Anna Monica in the house um so
Monica will be having a show on the
hustles on TV I mean we're com like the
way that this is working out you know
we're going to have a few different
shows kind of like
ABC um and uh those big networks but for
live streaming I think TV's going down
so thank you so much Monica for for
coming to the show um we have Sean uh um
chapen in the house he is a an artist
and he um he he will be coming on to the
hustle zone so um you know shout out to
you we got Ru in uh we got Ru we got um
Joe
Cross and M Mike Chavis Wendy um four
thank you Wendy for for coming in
hopefully we can collaborate soon but
folks yes um I really like this um this
uh this conversation today with our
guests um because you know we aim to
educate people and if we uh sorry I have
a frog in my throat but yeah we we
normally um
um we we aim to to educate people and
and and if we can help people too you
know with their their
foreclosures um I think that would be
great and I think that M uh I think that
um Matthew is doing a great job uh I
before we go back to him I just want to
make sure that everyone knows that this
today's episode is brought to you by Bow
creative ww. creative.com you know uh we
build websites that do more um they're
not typical WordPress websites we
actually build online businesses so that
you can run all your you could run your
business from the back end of your
website kind of like squar spaces but on
steroids and um and then also branding
gym which we offer companies unlimited
graphic design for a small fee and if
you guys are in the states I mean um you
want to leverage the US dollar cuz uh
you know our dollar is really crappy
over over here so you'll you'll get uh
really good deals on uh on unlimited
graphic design and of course make sure
you guys check out this episode and and
all the other episodes with our um with
our uh with our guest on hustlez own.tv
you can see courses you can see all
kinds of things on that
[Music]
well hello how are you guys doing
tonight my name is Ryan Perez I am the
host of hustle Zone TV uh owner and
founder and um you know also the owner
of bowai creative branding gym.com so um
how are you guys doing tonight it's been
uh you know been a couple of days since
since I've gone live the last live we
did was with Andy AET and that was
actually pretty awesome um a lot of you
guys came in to um to participate in
that show and he and you know for a
young guy you know he had a lot of uh of
great things to say um I'm going to ask
you guys just so that we can get the
show
um popping tonight make sure you you uh
um like us and you share you know bring
your friend friends because I don't
really uh pick guests that are not going
to to to to to give you some wisdom and
knowledge I I picked the guests that you
know have proven track records of
success and you know where you can learn
something from and you know tonight's
guest is actually someone that I really
wanted to uh um interview for for quite
some time um we've been
try it it yeah he's saying in the
background one year um
which is crazy because uh you know we've
been trying to get he was he called me
from his his uh his phone and uh he was
driving and we couldn't I couldn't get
him on to the live so it was crazy and
then we got him on again and then we had
a
quarrel um that I will not I will not
mention on this live but
um pretty interesting but yeah either
way um just one second so everyone take
time normally in my lives I I say I you
know I I ask everyone to take time to
share so please
share um I'm going to share right
now if you can all to share it
out I'm trying to log into my
okay
so trying to log in I can't okay all
right so I'm in
perfect and who's in the room tonight I
want to see who's in the room who do we
have who do we have in the
room okay we oh man we got Jason Franco
in the house we got Susan we got uh uh
Denzel uh we have lyy Lindsay hi um we
have Denzel in the house oh I already
read that and we got Mike Chavez in the
house and so I'm super excited for
tonight's guest uh he is the owner and
uh founder of uh of real estate Recovery
Group and he he saves you know like for
what I see he's he's helping the Common
Man and he's full of
knowledge I uh you know I'm super
excited to have him on the show I'm
going to let him tell you his story but
to everyone uh give a round of applause
for Matt marinov how's it going
Matt you super excited it doesn't look
like you're super
excited try to type my website in the
same time time I'm talking to you that's
not going to happen anyway it's all good
no I really am excited you know it's
funny Ryan we joke around before we
logged on is that you know it's been a
year now in the Mak trying to to to get
on a live feet together and talk so yeah
pretty uh it's exciting to actually be
on the online and and finally be able to
be in a form where you know I can let
people know really what's going on in
the uh in the real estate world people
uh most people don't want to know really
what's going on behind the scenes so I'm
excited to be here awesome well the
first we we'll get right into the
questions uh normally with the hustle
Zone uh people would you know get mad at
me if I didn't ask you you know the
first question we ask is what is your
story so tell us from the very beginning
even as a child like how did you grow up
how did you get to this position in your
life so uh ironically
enough I really wasn't a good student um
but I was always I always had like the
entrepreneurial feel and I guess as
young as like maybe 14 15 years old I
knew I wanted to be in real estate but I
really wasn't sure what I wanted to do
in real estate um but as I got older you
know you always go like to um uh you see
those like real estate books and you
look at the houses and you see the
pricing on it and you try to do like
price comparment and stuff like that um
fast forward until um my 20s believe it
or not I was a I was a a train operator
for um the New Jersey Transit the light
rail for about five years and then uh
from there um I got sick um um I've had
colitis my whole life and I
um I was fortunate enough to have a
brother and sister-in-law in the
mortgage business
and they said hey come on board you know
you know you're very personable people
like you uh this should be a really
great fit you know is it something that
you'd be interested I said yeah sure why
not so we uh we we ended up um building
a monster uh in their mortgage
organization and I worked in the post
closing clo post closing department and
honestly I really hated it um but then
an opportunity came along with a
National website and we were essentially
helping homeowners that were fsbos
moring their properties so they could
sell their properties privately and not
have to pay Real Estate
Commission here's a cash not everybody
could sell their property privately some
people actually needed to put the
properties on the MLS so the premise of
the site really was to show the
homeowners hey you can try to Market
your property but if it doesn't work you
know we have preferred agents that we
work with and it worked out really well
but then
2007 and you know the market started to
really change obviously because of the
tickler loans or the you know the
garbage loans or aka the banksters
really did a number on the mortgage
Community um loans started to change I
was talking to people and they were like
like well um you know can you get here
before my husband got home and I'm like
whoa wait a second I know I sound sexy
on the phone
but you know I'm you know it's not like
that then it was like you know the
husband was like hey can you talk can
you get here before my wife got home I
want to talk to you first I'm like well
I'm flattered it's not for me but you
know I guess that voice gets you again
but the reality is is that I was I was
speaking with homeowners didn't realize
the type of loan that they were in and
they were signing off on documents like
honestly I mean I don't know if you have
a mortgage on a house but I don't know
anybody actually takes the time to
actually re actually read the mortgage
documents read all the disclosures
through um but in the end uh the market
started to tank because of you know back
then it was called a short pay they c a
short sale I mean the reality is if
you've ever been involved in a short
sale there's nothing short about a short
sale it should really call it a short
long sale or long short sale because it
it takes forever uh but we've got it
done with science now um and through the
years it's been 12 years Ryan that I've
been in industry and I really I really
love helping people um that are in
trouble with their properties and they
don't know what their options are agents
are shying away from short sales and I'm
trying to educate them through my
partners program where they can you know
list the
property and
then they can sell the properties kind
of like they would sell normal real
estate and real estate Recovery Group
will be their back office right and
we've had really awesome
success working with agents that didn't
think a deal is going to go through
didn't think that the deal was possible
attorneys gave him bad advice um on all
sides we've had some very successful
wins with agents that normally would
have walked away from a transaction made
no commission we just helped some we
just helped an agent make
$24,000 in commission Ryan wow and if we
did not step in and we didn't get
involved the house was going to go to
sheriff sales and everything I talk
about Ryan is completely documented so
it's not like I'm just saying hey you
know what if you if you listen to what I
have to say I'm the greatest and that's
why I joke around all the time and I
tell people you know uh Facebook AKA
fake book because you're not you don't
really know what's going on behind the
scenes and I'm generally I generally
want to help people um people say all to
me all time you know keep it up great
work you know you seem really
sincere um and you know what you're
doing obviously is is is great because
the average person or the average
company that was involved in this for
many years stepped out of it they don't
want to be involved in it anymore they
feel like there's no money to be
involved in you know in short sell
industry can can I ask you a quick
question because I
mean what I'm missing a part of the
story is you know like with you being a
part of the company how are you driving
the success of the company like how are
how is it that you guys are doing so
well cuz I mean anyone could have been
in your situation and put together a
business maybe I don't know um but you
know you seem like someone that really
has it together in terms of you know
managing this business but but what what
what's the what's the thing that is
making you different to the reason why
you're why you're so successful at this
I want to tell you what there's a couple
different things one of the driving
forces for my shift in my company for
helping people so if you follow me on
Facebook you'll see all the time I say
like you know # RG know your options or
you know hash rrg Nationwide I say that
because my mother-in-law and my
father-in-law um they lost their house
the
foreclosure and they both said that if
they were in a position where they had
found somebody like myself maybe they
would have been able to keep their
property um so when things switched
around um you know years later they had
gotten divorced or what have you and she
ended up marrying another
gentleman and you know fast forward
three years ago which really was the
start of my kickoff for you know uh the
partners program or for the uh the
Avenue for people to figure
out do they have you know other options
other than just doing a short sale
because not everybody want to sell a
house so she was forced with
foreclosure again this would have been
two now two strikes so what happened was
um everybody said they couldn't help her
nobody wanted to get involved in it her
mortgage pay pay was going to go up like
500 5500 $600 a month she wouldn't have
been able to afford her mortgage mhm I
stepped in uh at the time it was a
streamline modification she was current
on her
mortgage and um everything was
remodified she brought a check for
$16.35 to the closing table which was
actually in my house uh when she was
here and her payment I think went up $68
a month versus the $5 $600 a month so
she was like you know don't you want to
help people save their houses and I was
always concerned with because you know
there's so many criminals out there
there's such a bad rap that everybody
tries to take advantage of people that
are in bad situations right and
obviously I'm not like that and people
once they get to know me or they watch
my videos and they see how quirky I can
be and joke
around it's almost like I'm trying to
invite them into my environment so they
understand a little bit about my life
and you know what I do uh it works out
it really does and I I think that you
know um I I a couple years ago we also
had some tragedy in my family my
father-in-law my dad actually passed
away on the same day Ryan oh no I'm
sorry to hear that it's okay I don't I
don't really share that story too much
but that was another driving force and I
told my wife I'm done I'm not doing this
anymore and she's like are you going to
commit suicide and I said no I don't
don't want to run my business the way
I'm running anymore I really want to
shift want to help and she goes okay so
I got rid of all my Partnerships and I
focused more on real estate Recovery
Group then I focused more on the
partners program very slowly and I've
been building it up and I really did a
lot of testing you know trying to like
prototype the type of Industry that I
want to go after and that's why I've
been really pushing it the last six
months the partners program and
businesses exploded
Nationwide with other individuals that
are agents are investors even attorneys
are calling me saying hey can you take a
look at this case I don't know what to
do you know I'm boxing the corner now
here's another thing that most people
won't do and they feel like well why
would you do it like there's not a lot
of money in it do it because it's the
right thing to do and by doing it think
about the self-advertisement you're
getting I'm GNA explain it to you like
this
we actually helped somebody they lost
their house to
foreclosure we were working on the file
the file was active they illegally not
legally illegally foreclosed on this guy
okay we got the Foreclosure
reversed that's virtually impossible in
this industry from what I'm being told
now we're working on its file right now
do a short sale on it he doesn't want a
foreclosure
the second guy that we're working with
now that we just picked up this
gentleman is in a situation where his
house is gone already he came to us when
it was gone but we had ref we were
reviewed all the documentation and when
I say documents this guy must have gave
us
like 4 500 documents and in it we had
found out that again he was foreclosed
on improperly mhm so we're in the
process of turning around his bankrupt
uh his
foreclosure and making his file active
again and he actually might have a a
huge lawsuit against the bank because
the bank told him pay off your second
loan because now we're close to the
modification he he went through the
modification process Ryan he he
completed it he paid off his second
mortgage as they told him to do it the
loan got service transferred to another
company and they foreclosed on his house
wow so you know most people would not
want to take on a case like that we love
cases like that and we'd love to try to
help people make a difference and that's
why I tell people like know your options
because quite honestly if you don't
really know what your options are you're
really going to put your head in the
sand mhm you're going to wait for the
knock on the front door and it's going
to be the sheriff and he's going to say
look you've been warned and there's
going to be a moving truck out front and
he's going to say you got 15 minutes
grab your belongings and then a moving
crew is going to come in there and
they're going to move all your stuff and
they're going to put it into a box in a
storage facility and you're going to be
like where do I live and and they're
going to look at you dead in the face
and go you should have thought of that
so I say instead of people going that
route and waiting till the last minute
and thinking why why why should I do
anything my neighbor down the street he
he was in his house for seven years and
they never foreclosed on him you know
why would somebody want to play Russ
roulette like that like that doesn't
make any sense at all that somebody
would want to risk the livelihood of a
family think about it my wife was 17
years old Ryan when she was away
mhm seriously she was away at college
she they they her mom called and said
hey we're going to get
divorced um there's a dumpster in the
front
yard the house is going to be going to
sale on uh Friday or that Monday or what
I think it was that
Monday uh the property was in
Connecticut and they said you need to
come home this week and get your
belongings otherwise it's going to get
thrown out she said I've got finals I I
I have finals I I have to take these
tests should look for the past or she
going to move to the Future so she
literally lost I was say about 99% of
her childhood gone erased like it didn't
even exist that's
scary so like you know when I tell
people like I you know I get phone calls
and they're like wow you know we have
kids in the school district and we're
not sure what we want to do yet
and you know we're hoping that you know
the bank is going to you know postpone
the sherff
sale when that share of sale is set it's
a freight train and it's coming right at
you you know there's very few things
that are going to be able
to
um stop the sheriff shell from
happening but it is it's very it's very
traumatic and I feel bad for the
children and with stuff like this
happens it's really super sad so you
know I guess if my message was to be
with your listeners to get across would
be if you know somebody who's in trouble
with their property and I don't really
care where it is in the United States I
don't even care if it's in Canada people
really need to know what their options
are before they lose their house the
sheriff sell before it's too late but
don't wait till the last minute because
it's harder for my team in me you know
it's not just me I have you know four
people total you know that work that
work with me and they're very talented
individuals and without them I couldn't
do what I do and without what I do they
couldn't do what they do so everybody
compliments everybody but I oversee the
operation uh there are people out there
that have had operations like this
they've shut them down for whatever
reason I only feel like my business is
just going to keep
growing monthly now and uh you know I'm
hoping to take uh world domination now
that but I definitely I I definitely you
know I'm very sincere and I I truly love
helping people and I'm all about you
know making sure that you know my team
is happy and that you know they're
making sure that our clients are happy
look the average business is opened from
9 to 5 whatever time zone it
is five days a week my company operates
seven days a week and sometimes listen I
it's almost like we are a big um
helpline organization if you may uh I
definitely I was say the last 12 years I
should get an honorary doctor doctor as
a therapist
from talking people down off the ledge
and understanding what their options are
and that's why I want to you know know
your options aspect of it because people
really don't know what their options are
and I'll say it a million times over
until people tell blew my face because
if you don't ask and you don't know and
I've asked a ton of stuff through the
years I would say about 20% of the deals
that we work on we actually settle the
mortgages and what I mean by settle the
mortgages the homeowner gets to keep in
stay in their house they get to keep
their
house and the actual mortgage would get
settled for less than full amount it's
not a short sale it's a settlement so if
somebody has money or has access to the
money and you have a loan that's
possibly something that could be settled
why not look that route the reason why
people don't look that route is because
they don't know the option is there Mak
sense yeah that makes sense and um have
you always been this caring I mean we
always like I can think of you know a
few people that have gone on the path of
helping others um you know just because
that's who they are and then there are
people that have had something traumatic
happen in their lives where they decide
you know what um I have more power to to
help people like have you have you been
like this all your
life yeah I think I've always been a
caring individual I will tell you this
though you know as a as a young child I
think I was
um scared about what other people
thought I was uh intimidated by certain
individuals there there were definitely
women or girls growing up that I thought
were very attractive and I would always
be like oh you know why would they pick
me I mean now I look like a big round
you know pumpkin but uh if you go on my
Facebook page you'll see I was quite a
handsome gentleman and I probably get a
posst for play Girl
magazine but um you know it's weird as
you get older and you get wiser yeah um
you know I picked my son up today from
school and he's like Dad you know do you
think you're going to write a book one
day and I'm actually working on two
different books one is about my actually
my life story which a lot of people
don't know about and I think people find
interesting and the other book would is
the industry that I'm in like I love
that movie The Big Short The Big Short
to me is such an inspirational movie and
if you haven't watched it and you're in
the real estate world you really should
watch they should make that mandatory
you should watch it there's a scene in
the movie where there there's two guys
from a firm a hedge fund firm and
they're looking at all these different
houses that were you know deserted and
they actually go and knock on the door
and they're asking for the homeowner and
the homeowner is saying I don't
understand why you asking for the the
homeowner's
dog and they're like what are you saying
the homeowner wrote the mortgage and in
his dog's name he's like I don't know so
that should just tell you how corrupt
the industry you was that you could
actually write a mortgage and your pet's
name I mean come on that's just shameful
and then you know even today I'll talk
with people on the inside of the bank
and they're like oh they should have
known what they were getting into or you
know they're like well you know if they
couldn't pay the mortgage they should
have let the house go or they sh the
paper were clearly stated what was going
to happen well I mean you know you're
going for surgery and you to get a
colonoscopy do you really read all the
paperwork and all the warning labels of
everything that's on there and what
they're going to do in that procedure
it's pretty self-explanatory they're
going to take a hose and they're going
to shove it up your ass all you want to
know is are you going to be knocked out
for that procedure
right same concept with a mortgage all
they want to know is is can I get my
mortgage and what's my what's my payment
going to Bay and let's face it the
premise for the crash really was that
the sale or the selling of the the the
promise of
homeownership and let's say you were
qualifi for a house for
$350,000 and the mortgage rep you know
looked at you like he was Jesus he's
partying the Red Sea and says it's 350
but what if I could get you into a house
for
700,000 and your payment is the same
people are like let's do it you know it
was like you know giving away candy the
you know the no the no do loans the the
no the credit loans the no
um employment information I mean just it
was it was a horrible time and it's
still there the banks have made specific
departments now in their
organization and a lot of things are
changing and a lot of things are going
to continuously change and Ryan this is
what I tell people and I know we talked
about this before we started but think
of it this way it's 200 uh almost 2008
right it it's a 10y year anniversary the
10y year anniversary of the iPhone that
just came out right
yeah think about the first cell phone
that you ever got or think about the
first iPhone that you got think about
the differences on the things in the
phone a long time you know the uh the
information the the uh the chips the the
the the functioning of how the phone
work changed right M it manifested
into something outstanding and
amazing so when people say to me a short
sell is a short sale that's [ __ ] a
short sale is not a short sale and if
you don't know what you're doing in this
industry you can
single-handedly drive a homeowner into
foreclosure and be liable for that
person essentially losing their house
because you didn't know what the hell
you were doing now you can hide behind
your real estate license all day long if
you want to but what it comes down to is
if somebody's in trouble with their
house this is not a case of you fake it
to you make it you better know what the
hell you're doing when you're dealing
with somebody who's in trouble with
their house and give them some options
and they might not want to talk right
away to you they might want to just you
know they want to you know deal with an
attorney but I got a ton of attorneys
now that want to do business with me and
do do business with me because they
don't want to do what I do they don't
have
access uh to the knowledge that my team
has that I have you know I couldn't do
what I do if it wasn't for you know Leah
if it wasn't for will if it wasn't for
Tommy if it wasn't for my other
Partnerships that I have with other
companies and I got this this to you ran
there's going to be a lot more
Partnerships coming in 2018 with other
companies other real estate companies
even attorney's office that want to do
business
because we understand the guidelines not
just in the tri- state area Jersey you
know Connecticut and New York I'm
talking
Nationwide can can I ask H how scalable
is this business I mean if you were to
you know let's say you had to take a a
couple of months
off
um and uh you know go on vacation or you
had to attend to someone that's sick in
the family you know can will your if or
if you decide you just don't want to do
the business anymore you know will this
Legacy carry on and and I mean and I'm
saying this knowing that you know what
you're talking about here is
innovation right you know you're talking
about you know just people being more
aware of their options Andre and and
these businesses being more accountable
so it seems like that wave is riding
anyways but the fact that you guys have
specialized knowledge you know it's
great that you guys are helping people
but you know how can you maintain
you know the growth of this this this
new industry like what's how what's your
do you have a strategy in ensuring that
your legacy never gets forgotten so I'm
not going to divulge why I'm smiling
because yes I have a
plan uh what's thinking of a master plan
something something inside my mind I
whatever yeah I do I but I got I do have
an end game my end game is to uh um try
to grow the business um and have
partners and that's why I talk about the
partners program because there's there's
always so much that we can do um we
don't want to be you know the people
that has to collect every single
document that we actually have to trace
and track somebody um one of the systems
that I've implemented uh in my system um
and I'm not trying to sell the product
but I love it it's a system called track
with ease and uh he actually he
literally just sold um like he has a
system it's a CRM it's great for
attorneys uh for realtors investors even
tit comp if you want to tr track files
um and it's making things a lot easier
for my staff uh reminders are set
automatically if a task is not fulfilled
it will ring that person to death until
they fulfill that task or basically
saying I'm not doing it and technology
is obviously going to be a big game
changer for my company and you know
joining with that company track withe
the name of the company is actually
called track
with.com and people can go on and take a
look at the software itself um it's made
things a lot easier for me I know people
that have blown up their business by
over 100 200% because of it so what's
going to help me in the future
technology um having the staff that I
have on hands now um being able to grow
internally and take those people and try
to eventually push them into more of my
type of role but I think at the end of
the day like no nobody really has my
quote unquote drive like look Steve Jobs
he couldn't build a phone he had an idea
he had a concept he he had something
that he wanted to run with and apple did
it and you know he was able to do many
things you know with that particular
product my product my branding is uh
myself my name at marinov um anybody
who's I guess a mover and the Shaker in
the industry now is starting to know
notice what I do and why I do it and I
think um you know the product that we're
pumping out where we're we we have a
system in place and it can be duplicated
and it can be replicated and it doesn't
just have to be you know in my office
environment and that's why we we go
we're going to grow as much as people
want to grow with us uh I I I have a a
meeting um set up with with a um
National real estate
company uh this gentleman has eight
markets that he's in and he's projecting
next year he'd like to try to do about
150 short sales with me that's a lot for
one individual for one group you know to
have that can my company fulfill it yes
so I guess to the long the long short
version the short long version is in the
future you know where do I see my
company going I see my company growing
um to hopefully have you know two or
three of me in it and I'll be able to
you know raise more
awareness of you know the market that
we're in this Market's not going away
the media doesn't talk about it there is
going to be another influx of people
that are going to be defaulting on loan
modifications and depending on who that
person is as an
investor or the mortgage company they're
going to say well they've already had
their modification limit you know it's
liquidation time they've got to sell the
property and not everybody wants to sell
right you know run some some people want
to stay in the house another six months
to a year and I believe that I think
that people should have that option
people should be able to stay in the
house um until you know know the end of
the school year and we we are helping
people that cannot qualify for programs
um to be able to
prolong um the you know the time frame
from the Foreclosure or at least stop
stop so so the Judgment doesn't take
hold and
that's in this industry people don't
realize once you get the judgment on you
that's when this that's when the dance
can start the legal fees jump up
and from there it could be six months it
could be two years at any time you're
literally playing it's like a dangerous
game of Russian Roulette depending on
where you are and when the sale date
hits in your county in your
state uh country wherever it is you got
to check you got to find out you know is
is is my house on a chopping block this
week my company does all that
Anna you're right there is a is a great
uh need for single family dwellings Ryan
I didn't I wasn't paying attention I
guess people were making comments yeah I
I have the comments come on the screen
just so that we can get you know get to
talk in and and stuff so we kill two
birds with one we kill two birds with uh
sorry with one stone um I'm going to
break here for a second and I'm just
going to acknowledge some of the people
that are in the room okay um so uh Anna
thank you for you like if you could get
if there was a participation award you
would get that award so thank you so
much Anna Monica in the house um so
Monica will be having a show on the
hustle Zone TV I mean we're com like the
way that this is working out you know
we're going to have a few different
shows kind of like
ABC um and uh those big networks but for
live streaming I think TV's going down
so thank you so much Monica for for
coming to the show um we have Sean
um chapen in the house he is a an artist
and he um he he he will be coming on to
the hostle zone so um you know shout out
to you we got R in um we got Ru we got
um Joe
Cross and M uh Mike Chavez uh Wendy U
four thank you Wendy for for coming in
hopefully we can collaborate soon but
folks yes um I really like this um this
this conversation today with our guests
um because you know we aim to educate
people and if we uh sorry I have a frog
in my throat but yeah we we normally
um we we aim to to educate people and
and and if we can help people too you
know with their their
foreclosures um I think that would be
great and I think that M uh I think that
um Matthew's doing a great job uh
I before we go back to him I just want
to make sure that everyone knows that
this today's episode is brought to you
by bot creative ww. creative.com you
know uh we build websites that do more
um they're not typical WordPress
websites we actually build online
businesses so that you can run all your
you could run your business from the
back end of your website kind of like
squar spaces but on steroids and um and
then also branding gym which we offer
companies unlimited graphic design for a
small fee and if you guys are in the
states I mean um you want to leverage
the US dollar cuz uh you know our dollar
is really crappy over here so you'll
you'll get uh really good deals on uh on
unlimited graphic design and of course
make sure you guys check out this
episode and and all the other episodes
with our um with our uh with our guest
on hustlez own.tv you you can see
courses you can see all kinds of things
on that on on our website and it's all
for free and the last thing is uh please
in order to support our initiative um
you know we're asking people to go to
ww. gofundme.com
uh hustle zoney TV um you know donate
$50 $25 to help us um continue this
project and and talking to folks like
Matt um you know that are helping people
that are you know that are because
entrepreneurs help
communities and so we want to interview
these entrepreneurs and record their
stories um we want to um allow people to
access it for free we want to help young
entrepreneurs get access to a lot of
information and we want to give you give
our our audience honest content not fake
Mumble jumbo um you know the 10 steps on
how to stand on one knee um type uh you
know material so um you guys definitely
want to check us out on GoFundMe um so
that you can donate a little and then we
we have like flashy t-shirts that we
give away uh when you donate so um
please check us out on the GoFundMe page
and we're going to get back to Matt so
uh I I'm going to ask you a question uh
Matt what is
your besides the apart from your
business like what is your um
if you had one thing to say about
success what would you
say as far as being successful or what
it takes to be suc what it sorry what it
takes to be
successful well you know I I guess
failure uh being able to learn from
failure uh being to understand and take
what you know what a no does to people
being able to have a door shut in your
face
being able to as my dad used to say
going up and touching the door knob of
somebody's door people are afraid to
touch you the door knob or or in the
doorbell they're afraid that they're
gonna get shock or that they're going to
burn their finger or it's going to be
too cold I I would say every failure is
going to be bring you closer to a
success and it's true what they say
whatever doesn't kill you makes you
stronger um this industry is really
toughened me up um I don't want to say
I've made enemies cuz I haven't that I
know of um but I know that I've
disappointed partners that I've been
with
because I had more of a vision of trying
to help people and I think that the
people that I was dealing with in
certain
situations I I guess I I tend to to push
away from those type of mentality
so I guess you know being able to handle
a no handle
rejection uh I am getting a lot more
people Ryan that are coming at me now
they want to do business with me uh some
tend to be or act shady uh if you're a
shady person don't reach out to me I
don't want to do business with you uh if
you're genuine and you want to help
people that are in trouble with their
properties and want them to know the
options
look I guess I know as an agent or as an
investor you don't make any money unless
you can get that property but at the end
of the day they really should have the
right whether they can keep their house
or not and I know that some people don't
want to do business with me because
they're afraid that if the homeowner
asks me do I have a chance to keep in my
house yeah I'm going to say yeah I'm
going to I'm going to acknowledge it
they should have the opportunity right
and I do offer you know I guess it has
to you have to watch How It's offered
but I guess like a marketing fee uh or a
Consulting consulting fee um for
transactions that you know don't work
out the way that the the
prospect slash investor realtor brings
towards me um so I've been asked to not
talk about the compensation in great
detail um it's not a tremendous amount
of money but it's enough to say that hey
you know if you did 15 minutes to an
hour of work and it didn't go to the way
you wanted there's nothing wrong with
getting a consulting fee you get a$ 1099
you know or a marketing fee or
whatever um
and I guess you know when it comes down
to success just don't give up I'm the
perfect example of somebody that I've
had to start over in this industry four
times because I just didn't like the way
the road was paved so I I guess I took
sticks of dynamite and bulldozers and
exudates ex and just I I just made my
own Road are you are you afraid of um
because you had mentioned that you don't
really have much enemies but you know
normally when you're you're you're
changing the industry or you're you know
spearheading
a revolution in the way that people are
thinking that there are enemies out
there and in this case when you're
dealing with you know thousands you know
Millions even um you know some people
think that you're digging in their
pocket so are you afraid of your life
you know are you afraid of you know that
kind of backlash on your family and and
whatnot if it if you become too
successful I think at the end of the day
honestly I tell my wife all the time you
know I'm
insured so uh if anybody's going to be
taken out I guess it's going to be me so
you know kudos to whoever does it
because they'll get the last laugh um
I'm more kid but as far as you know
threat I'm not really too worried about
that I think that if I was to actually
get um a podcast
show um or some type of a radio show I
don't necessarily need a TV show that
tot at least 50 pound but I don't think
I really need that type but I think if I
got a radio show if I had a podcast show
I think it would pick up a lot of
momentum because I would do a lot of
Q&A with my team and I think people
would be Blown Away about their
rights and the banking industry Ryan I'm
going to say I won't say uh a specific
investor um banking institution but I
will say that
they're not your friend when you're in
default I will say that they say be
leery of third party companies that
charge a fe for services we do it for
free be careful what you get for be
careful what you wish for and I will
also say and this might shock you it
might
not they offer the program they don't
have to offer the solution to help you
with the program
so let's just
say there's a situation and you're
trying to qualify for a short sale and
being that your income is more than
enough to pay the mortgage and you're
saying it's not and they're saying it is
they can actually deny you short sale
most people don't know that wow on a
modification side of
it I've heard people fail modifications
for 15 cents
Ryan 15 freaking
cents $16 $86 here and there all they
have to do is just tell a person who's
in
trouble you know uh it's the plaintiff
and the defendant the plaintiff should
just tell the defendant listen if you
move this item line item off of your
income and outgoing expense you're
qualified
they are told specifically
not instruct the homeowners right that's
crazy 15 cents somebody lost their house
for 15 cents and actually made them do a
short sale in their
house now if they knew that they were
off by 15 cents are you freaking kidding
me MH so this is where it gets hairy and
if I said if I had my own TV show it
would get real up in there real quick
and I would call out the actual name
that they talk about on the big
short and that's an actual name that was
written in a mortgage in a dog's name
and as a lending institution you can't
help somebody who's off by 15 cents keep
their house I say
gfy that's my
abbreviation wow it's insane wow
but nobody talks about it Ryan nobody
talks about the elephant in the room
nobody wants to talk about why is Matt
marinov so pumped to talk about the POR
program why is Matt marinov telling
people short celles are not dead they're
not
dinosaurs what does Matt marinov know
that other people don't know well I'll
tell you this I've got connections
inside the banks after 12 years of the
industry
they don't think that I don't have
people on the inside of the banks
telling me what's going on come on it's
ridiculous people do evaluations they
call a Bo it's called a broker price
opinion it's a freaking joke when they
do the the appraisals on the properties
those things get swayed towards the bank
side not towards getting the deal done
in most
situations now do I have proof of that
yeah of course I've got proof of it I've
got individuals that are willing to do a
documentary rying with me and talk about
how the banking industry has
successfully [ __ ] up the housing
market to me that's pretty sexy am I
worried about being assassinated by a
realtor an
investor no am I worried about being
assassinated by the banking industry yes
m
wow that's but I'm okay but I'm okay
with it yeah I found I found my calling
I do renovate houses I do make money
renovating houses I'm not a
millionaire I'm okay with what I do but
at the end of the day for me it's about
letting people know their options right
that's it they need to know and if I
have to be the voice of reason for doing
it I'll be the voice of reason until
somebody says to me Matt okay you can
start calling out Bank names you can
start calling out individuals in
Banks I'm not going to do it but once
that time comes true and I can do it and
I know I'm allowed to do it shit's gonna
get real real quick
Ryan I hear you wow Matt thank you so
much for uh for coming on the show and
sharing your story and you know that's
it it it it hits right to the core but
hopefully people that are watching today
can learn a thing or two and and if
you're in um a situation you need to hit
up Matt um we have uh his website here
um you know ww. stop forclosure doco you
know check him out folks because
uh you know you you ought to know your
options you ought to know what's
happening with your life I mean this is
your livelihood this is your home this
is where you're going to be sleeping
this is where your children are growing
up so you know you definitely want to
follow Matt you want to check out his
website so Matt before we close out we
got a lightning round um where I ask you
some
questions um so just to get off a little
bit uh get off the topic a bit but uh I
only like
women there's nothing wrong with
anything else but I only like
women okay so first question texting or
talking
you know what texting's good but I love
to
talk okay um rock or
rap rock or
rap I would probably say rap rap uh
favorite city in the US besides where
you
live you know what I haven't been there
in many many years but I'd have to say
um there's a city in um Florida called
Hollywood Florida lot of fun memories
there for me growing up as a child
awesome uh and why do you um why do you
you have a lot of photos with you and
your children you know sticking up their
finger at the camera what does that
mean so this
symbolizes I'm talking to you
I'm I'm I'm trying to get your attention
you need to know your options there you
go I want people to know I'm watching
them awesome uh what's the last song
that you've
downloaded I can't say as a bad
phone nickname your parents used to call
you uh they used to call me uh hoe cuz
my middle name is how
mhm so they call me hoe and my dad used
to call my brother me starski and
Hutch St yeah so I was still asking my
brother was
Hut would you rather uh would you rather
be able to speak every language in the
world uh or be able to talk to
animals can I can I if I say animals can
I still speak to you know to you know
English or no no
English I guess I'd have to go with
every language besides talking
animal some people say different things
uh favorite favorite
holiday Father's
Day how how long does it take to you uh
okay I'll skip this question um fill in
the
blank Taylor Swift
is pretty pretty damn sexy okay and what
age do you want to
retire I don't ever want to retire I
love what I do and last question is is
it wrong for a vegetarian to eat animal
crackers
yes awesome
well Matt thank you so much for coming
on to the hustle Zone how was your
experience I love it man I love it um
you know I mean I'm faded out I'm like
dark and ashy I look like I'm getting
ready to stroke out but I mean other
than that you know I love it I love the
setup man I love watching your videos I
love what you're doing I love what
you're pumping out um you get it um you
definitely become you know a force to
been reckon with on Facebook people in
my area you know over here in Jersey
they know who you are you know they they
watch your you know the hustle zone so
you're definitely making ways man keep
it up oh thank you and um the last thing
before you
go I'm going to need you to uh we have a
we have a tradition on the hustle Zone
but before I before we do that uh where
do where can people find you besides the
the website that I put
up um so my we that website you know uh
www stop forclosure
Doo um the hashtags that I throw threw
up you could find me on the hashtags
that are on there you know re hash re
you know Nationwide
re I'm sorry rrg
rrg uh and the short sale lawn mod
whatever stuff like that awesome and so
the the last thing is we're going to do
a call and response so I'm going to say
welcome to the and I need you to scream
out loud as you possibly can the hustle
Zone um you know we've I've had people
scream loud and wake up their babies and
and all kinds of things but it's the
tradition so we're just going to have to
do it so I'll say welcome to that and
you say hustle
zone right okay so one two three welcome
to the hustle
[Music]
Zone man sounds like you got a singing
voice there man shoot I I do I do do you
sing I do actually what what do you
sing um I like older songs not like you
know the new stuff that's out there K
can you sing for us right now
no turn your shower on and I'll sing for
you all right sounds good well uh thank
you so much Matt for for coming into the
hustle Zone um you know again thank you
for doing what you're doing for the
people and you know I and and may God
bless you and and and folks thank you
guys so much for for for coming into the
hustle Zone as well like I like Anna
you're killing it with the
participation um but yeah so folks uh
make sure you hold on one
second we're just getting our screens up
so like I said uh this episode is
brought to you by my digital agency
ww.bbc creative.com so um if you want
websites that actually do more that
convert leads and and whatnot you
definitely want to chat me up um and
then head to our website ww. branding
jim.com to get unlimited graphic design
because there's no reason why you know
companies are hiring you know graphic
designers for like 40 grand for the for
the year you know 400 bucks will get you
unlimited gra graphic design per month
and that's Canadian dollars so you could
imagine how much that is that's probably
$300 you know um it in the US so you
definitely want to hit me up for that
and um and don't forget to check us out
on GoFundMe and oh before I I let you
guys go I I put this graphic up because
I want everyone to know and again this
is a wrong graphic because it's off by
1% but you know where we're putting our
funds is employees we want to hire
people to create content to find guys
like Matt um and tell their stories and
we want to do it on a larger scale than
me in my living room um so we definitely
want people to to you know to donate
something you know to help help help us
out so that we can tell more stories so
um thank you guys all for coming into
the hustle Zone and I'll talk to you
later
[Music]